AGUSTÍN LAVANDERO IVELIC

८+569 990 773 42 • ■ alavandero@fen.uchile.cl • **in** www.linkedin.com/in/alavanderoi

Summary

Business professional with a degree in Economic Sciences from Universidad de Chile, with work experience in the financial market and economic consulting. I completed my professional internship at the consulting firm Econsult S.A. and am currently working as a Business Intelligence Analyst at Credicorp Capital Corredores de Bolsa SPA. I have strong skills in analysis and problem-solving, enjoy working with programming software, and thrive on interacting with different areas.

EDUCATION

Pontificia Universidad Católica de Chile • Santiago, Chile

November 2022 - September 2023

Diploma • Python and Data Science

Facultad de Economía y Negocios, Universidad de Chile • Santiago, Chile

March 2017 – August 2022

Business • Bachelor's Degree in Economics

March 2003 – November 2017

Primary and Secondary Education

Work Experience

Credicorp Capital Corredores de Bolsa SPA • Santiago, Chile

 $January\ 2023-Present$

Business Intelligence Analyst

- Data collection and analysis to define company strategies.
- Preparation of reports for presentations, boards, and internal management.
- Management control and development of KPIs to evaluate the performance of employees, products, and clients.
- Support to different areas of the company to automate daily processes.
- Construction of derivative valuation models with Python.
- Active participation in internal and regulatory audits.
- Preparation of the annual budget based on projections, KPIs, and strategies.

Econsult S.A • Santiago, Chile

March 2022 – August 2022

Economic Analyst Intern

- Experience in research, data analysis, and arbitrage.
- Preparation of presentations and analysis of different economic sectors with multiple work teams.
- · Creation of new economic indicators through web-scraping and automation of semi-annual reports.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming Languages: Python, SQL, R, Power BI
- Others: MS Office (Excel), Rmarkdown

Languages

- · Native Spanish
- Advanced English (Houston, TX 2016 2017)

Extracurricular Activities

- Diplomas in Pasta, Risotto, and Pizza at French Culinary School ECOLE
- Rugby, Camping, Hiking